Fried, John H. E.; Papers ger014
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Writings of John H. E. Fried, 1931-1990; 10
  - Publications by John H. E. Fried, 1929-1990; 10.1; 252 file folders
    - Encyclopedia articles, Undated; 10.1.111 (Box 14 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 55-101)
      - "South-East Asia Treaty Organization (SEATO)", Typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 90)
      - "Summit Conferences", Clipping, typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 91)
      - "Swastika", 1955; Typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 92)
      - "Totalitarianism", Typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 93)
      - "Trade Agreements", Clippings (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 94)
      - "United Nations: The First Ten Years", Clipping (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 95)
      - "Utilitarianism", Clipping, typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 96)
      - "Utopia", 1955; Clipping, typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 97)
      - "War Crimes", ca. 1962; Clipping, typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 98)
      - "War Crimes Trials", 1949; Typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 99)
      - "Warsaw Pact", Clipping, typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 100)
      - "World Population Problems", 1958; Clipping, typescript (Box 14 (10.1.111-Encyclopedia articles), Folder 101)
    - Reviews, published and unpublished, 1934-1982; 10.1.112 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 1-82)
      - "Americas Foreign Policy: The Great Debate". Multiple review, clipping, 1943 (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 1)
      - Anderson, Paul B. People Church and State in Modern Russia, 1945; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 2)
      - Andrews, John B. Labor Law in Action, 1938; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 3)
      - Appleman, John Alan. Military Tribunals and International Crimes, January 1955; Photocopy (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 4)
      - Benton, Wilbourn E./Georg Grimm. Nuremberg. German Views of the War Trials, 1970; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 5)
      - Die Beziehungen zwischen Deutschland und der Sowjetunion 1939-1941. Ed. Alfred Seidl, 1949; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 6)
      - Bothe, Michael. Das Völkerrechtliche Verbot des Einsatzes Chemischer und Bakteriologischer Waffen, 1975; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 7)
      - Bottome, Edgar M. The Balance of Terror; Possony, Stefan T./J.E. Pournelle. The Strategy of Technology, 1972; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 8)
      - Boyle, Francis A. World Politics and International Law, June 1986; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 9)
      - Bretton, Henry L. Stresemann and the Revision of Versailles, 1953; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 10)
      - Brooks, Robert R. R. Unions of Their Own Choosing; Harris, Herbert. American Labor, 1939; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 11)
      - Brown, Seyom. New Forces in World Politics, March 1975; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 12)
      - Brown, William Adams Jr. The Future Economic Policy of the United States, September 1944; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 13)
      - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. Perspectives on Peace, September 1962; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 14)
      - Clark, Marjorie R./S. Fanny Simon. The Labor Movement in America, 1938; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 15)
      - Crosser, Paul K. Ideologies and American Labor, 1941; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 16)
      - Cyprian, Tadeusz/Jerzy Sawicki. Nuremberg in Retrospect, 1967; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 17)
      - De Viti de Marco, A. Principii di Economia Finanziaria, 1936; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 18)
      - Dinstein, Yoram. The Defense of "Obedience to Superior Orders" in International Law; Müller-Rappard, Ekkehard. L'Ordre Supérieur Militaire et la Responsabilité Pénale du Subordonné, October 1967; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 19)
      - Drost, Pieter N. The Crime of State, 1959; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 20)
      - Ebenstein, William. The Nazi State, January 30, 1943; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 21)
      - Edwards, David V. Arms Control in International Politics, March 1970; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 22)
      - Esslinger, William. Politics and Science, 1955; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 23)
      - Fantini, Oddone. La tutela del lavoro nell' ordinamento giurdico italiano e nella legislazione internazionale, 1934; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 24)
      - Faust, Fritz. Das Potsdamer Abkommen und seine Völkerrechtliche Bedeutung, April 1960; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 25)
      - Fawcett, J.E.S. The Law of Nations, 1969; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 26)
      - Ferencz, Benjamin B. Less Than Slaves, July 1981; typescript, photocopy (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 27)
      - Glassner, Martin Ira. Access to the Sea for Developing Land-Locked States, 1973; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 28)
      - Glueck, Sheldon. War Criminals, 1946; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 29)
      - Goldschmidt, Bertrand. The Atomic Complex, 1982; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 30)
      - Hagen, Paul. Germany after Hitler, September 1944; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 31)
      - Hamilton, Edith. The Great Age of Greek Literature, January 30, 1943; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 32)
      - Heiden, Konrad. Der Fuehrer; Hamburger, L. How Nazi Germany Has Controlled Business, 1944; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 33)
      - Hiller, Kurt (ed.). After Nazism - Democracy? Weber August. A New Germany in a New Europe, 1945; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 34)
      - Hoffmann, Gerhard. Strafrechtliche Verantwortung im Völkerrecht, January 1964; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 35)
      - International Labour Office. Labour Courts. An International Survey of Judicial Systems for the Settlement of Disputes, 1938; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 36)
      - Israel and the United Nations, 1957; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 37)
      - Jenks, Wilfred. Human Rights and International Labour Standards, 1962; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 38)
      - Jeschek, Hans-Heinrich. Die Verantwortlichkeit der Staatsorgane nach Völkerstrafrecht, 1952; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 39)
      - Justiz und NS-Verbrechen, 1971; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 40)
      - Kohn, Hans (ed.). German History, Some New German Views, 1954; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 41)
      - Kuczynski, Jurgen. Germany; Seydewitz, Max. Civil Life in Wartime Germany, December 1945; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 42)
      - Le May, Curtis. Mission with LeMay, 1965; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 43)
      - Lengyel, Emil. The Changing Middle East, 1960; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 44)
      - Lindsay, Kenneth. Towards a European Parliament, April 1960; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 45)
      - London, Kurt. How Foreign Policy Is Made, 1949; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 46)
      - Lord Russell of Liverpool. The Knights of Bushido, 1958; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 47)
      - Monaco, Riccardo. Le Instituzioni Internazionali di Cooperazione Europea, 1960; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 48)
      - Nash, Vernon. The World Must Be Governed, September 1949; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 49)
      - Neal, Fred Warner. War and Peace and Germany, 1962; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 50)
      - Newman, Bernard. Balkan Backgrounds; Gross, Feliks. Crossroads of Two Continents, February 1946; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 51)
      - Nizer, Louis. What To Do With Germany, June 1944; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 52)
      - The Nuremberg Trials. "Blue Series", Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 53)
      - "On War and Peace, Failures and Hopes". Multiple review, clipping, 1942 (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 54)
      - Phillips, Robert. American Government and Its Problems, 1942; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 55)
      - Pigors, Paul/L.C. McKenney/T.O. Armstrong. Social Problems in Labor Relations, 1939; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 56)
      - Queneudec, Jean-Pierre. La Responsibilité international de l'Etat pour les fautes personnelles de ses agents, 1966; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 57)
      - Quilici, Nello. Banca Romana, August 15, 1936; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 58)
      - Reel, A. Frank. The Case of General Yamashita, September 1950; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 59)
      - Richardson, J. Henry. Industrial Relations in Great Britain, 1939; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 60)
      - Rosenthal, Alfred. Nietzsche's "Europäisches Rasse-Problem". ("Der Kampf um die Erdherrschaft"), 1935; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 61)
      - Roucek, Joseph. Twentieth Century Political Thought, September 1946; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 62)
      - Schnorr, Gerhard. Das Arbeitsrecht als Gegenstand internationaler Rechtsetzung, 1960; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 63)
      - Schwarzschild, Leopold. World in Trance. From Versailles to Pearl Harbor, 1942; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 64)
      - Shirer, William L. The Rise and Fall of the Third Reich; Taylor, A. J. The Origins of World War II; Hitler's Secret Book, ca. 1961; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 65)
      - Shirer, Willliam L. The Rise and Fall of the Third Reich, Typescript, notes (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 66)
      - Taylor, A.J.P. The Origins of World War II. Notes (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 67)
      - Hitler's Secret Book. Notes (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 68)
      - Shirlaw, G.B./L.E. Jones. You and the Peace, February 1945; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 69)
      - Somerville, John. Soviet Marxism and Nuclear War. An International Debate, September 1983; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 70)
      - Sørensen, Max (ed.). Manual of Public International Law, 1968; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 71)
      - Speer, Albert. Inside the Third Reich, 1971; Clipping (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 72)
      - Stavrianos, L.S. The Promise of the Coming Dark Age, December 1978; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 73)
      - Stonequist, Everett V. The Marginal Man, ca. 1939; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 74)
      - Strasser, Otto/Michael Stern. Flight from Terror, March 27, 1943; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 75)
      - Taylor, Telford. Nuremberg and Vietnam; an American Tragedy, December 1971; Clipping, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 76)
      - Tesauro, Giuseppe. Il Finanziamento delle Organizzazioni Internaziolani, ca. 1969; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 77)
      - Troeger, Heinrich. Der Kapitalverkehr im deutschen Divisenrecht insbesondere die Verwaltung ausländischer Vermögen in Deutschland, ca. 1934; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 78)
      - Verwey, Wil D. Economic Development, Peace and International Law. Notes, 1972 (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 79)
      - Wilkins, William J. The Sword and the Gavel, 1981; Reprint, typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 80)
      - Wise, Maurice K. Requisition in France and Italy, November 1944; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 81)
      - Woetzel, Robert K. The Nuremberg Trials in International Law, 1960; Typescript (Box 15 (10.1.112-Reviews, published and unpublished), Folder 82)
    - Translations by Fried from Italian into German, 1932-1936; 10.1.113 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 83-95)
      - Book reviews, translated from Italian into German, 1930s (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 83)
      - Del Vecchio, Giorgio. "Staat und Staatengesellschaft", 1936; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 84)
      - Del Vecchio, Giorgio. "Über die Staatlichkeit des Rechtes", undated; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 85)
      - Fanno, Marco. "Irrtümer in der Zeit als Ursachen wirtschaftlicher Schwankungen", 1932; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 86)
      - Fanno, Marco. "Die reine Theorie des Geldmarktes", 1933; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 87)
      - Fasiani, Mauro. "Der gegenwärtige Stand der reinen Theorie der Finanzwissenschaft in Italien", 1933; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 88)
      - Fossati, Eraldo. "Der Beitrag des Jean François Melon zur Finanzlehre", 1933; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 89)
      - Fubini, Renzo. "Über Wesen und Grenzen der finanzwirtschaftlichen Theorie", 1933; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 90)
      - Griziotti, Benvenuto. "Die Besoldungsverhältnisse der Beamtschaft und die neuere Entwicklung der Besoldungspolitik in Italien", ca. 1932; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 91)
      - Griziotti, Benvenuto. "Finanztheorie und Finanzrecht", 1936; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 92)
      - Papi, Giuseppe Ugo. "Die grundlegende Ursache der wirtschaftlichen Schwankungen", 1933; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 93)
      - Ricci, Umberto. "Die Kurve des Geldnutzens und die Theorie des Sparens", 1932; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 94)
      - Ricci, Umberto. "Theorie des Monopols mit zeitlich veränderlichen Preisen", 1935; Reprint (Box 15 (10.1.113-Translations by Fried from Italian into German), Folder 95)
  - Speeches, 1931-1989; 10.2; 113 file folders
    This sub-series includes speeches delivered at conferences, at university gatherings, as well as private lectures.
    - Lecture correspondence, 1949-1954 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 96)
    - Lecture correspondence, 1957-1962 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 97)
    - Lecture correspondence, notes, 1966-1990 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 98)
    - List of speeches, 1950-1990 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 99)
    - "Die Gleichheit im Wahlrecht". Advertisement, Vienna, 1931 May 08 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 100)
    - "Die Stellung der Bevoelkerung zu Recht und Rechtspflege". Advertisement, Vienna, 1936 April 20 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 101)
    - "Bevoelkerung und Rechtspflege". Advertisement, Vienna, 1936 June 10 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 102)
    - "Stab in the Back Propaganda", 1941; Typescript (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 103)
      New School lecture.
    - "The Plight of labor in Germany and Italy". Letter, Princeton, NJ, 1941 November 13 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 104)
    - "Military Determinism and the Rights of Men". Advertisement, New School, 1942 January 07 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 105)
    - Radio speeches, 1942 August (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 106)
    - "Germany, a Problem for the Post-War World". Advertisement, Summer Institute for Social Progress at Wellesley, 1943 June (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 107)
    - "How Fast Is Germany Cracking?" Radio talk, 1943 November 07 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 108)
    - Untitled radio talk, 1943 December 26; Typescript (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 109)
    - "The Prospect for Lasting Peace". Letter, Montreal, 1945 January 17 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 110)
    - Speech at Women's Canadian Club, Ritz Carlton Hotel, Montreal, 1945 November 23; Newspaper clipping (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 111)
    - Midweek review, Canadian Broadcasting Company, 1946 June 19; Mimeographed text (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 112)
    - American Political Science Association. Letter, Cleveland, 1946 December (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 113)
    - "The Nuremberg Trials and Historical Sciences". Mimeographed text, 1950 September (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 114)
    - "Freedom and Authority". Twelfth Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion in their Relation to the Democratic Way of Life, New York, 1951 September 04-1951 September 07; Reprint (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 115)
    - Kiwanis Club, Herkimer, NY, 1952 June; Speech text, clippings (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 116)
    - ALES-CIO Seminar. Program, 1952 September 05-1952 September 19 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 117)
    - United Nations Weekend, Schenectady, NY, 1952 October 24-1952 October 26; Advertisements (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 118)
    - "What's New at the UN?" Advertisements, notes. Columbia University; December 10, 1952; Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences, March 3, 1953, Undated (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 119)
    - Anthropology Club, Hunter College, 1954 March 17; Notes (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 120)
    - "Technical Assistance. What It Means, How It Works". 9th Annual United Nations Seminar, 1954 November 22-1954 November 25; Advertisement (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 121)
    - "Treatment of Non-German Collaborators after World War II". Notes, Yivo Institute, 1956 January 23 (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 122)
    - "The Promotion of Anti-semitism through the Abuse of Democratic and Socialist Concepts". Jerusalem, 1957 August; Reprint, typescript (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 123)
    - B'nai B'rith, Gloversville, NY, 1960 December 04; Notes, clipping (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 124)
    - Human Rights Day Speech, Kathmandu, 1964 December 10; Notes (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 125)
    - United World Federalists, Twentieth General Assembly, Washington, DC, 1966 June 16-1966 June 19; Program (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 126)
    - "The Law and Judgment of the International Military Tribunal at Nuremberg". The National Lawyers Club, Washington, D.C., 1966 November 05; Correspondence, programs (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 127)
    - National Lawyers Guild, 29th National Convention, NY, 1967 February 10-1967 February 13; Program (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 128)
    - "Legality of US Intervention in Vietnam". University of Pennsylvania, 1967 March 01; Notes, correspondece, clippings (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 129)
    - "The Friend-Foe Syndrome". Pacem in Terris Institute, Manhattan College, 1967 April 14; Typescripts, program, conference materials (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 130)
    - "How Can We End the Vietnam War?" Columbia University, 1968 February 19; Note cards (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 131)
    - "Is American Military Intervention in Vietnam Legal?" Columbia University, 1968 March 13; Note cards (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 132)
    - "The Illegality of U.S. Demands for 'Reciprocity' as a Condition for the Cessation of Bombing of North Vietnam". World Conference of Lawyers for Vietnam, Grenoble, 1968 July 06-1968 July 10; Mimeographed text (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 133)
    - New York Public Library rally, 1969 May 17; Notes, advertisement (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 134)
    - Lawyers' Convocation on Vietnam. Church Center for the United Nations, 1969 October 15; Note cards, correspondence (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 135)
    - Moratorium speech on Vietnam, Columbia University, 1969 October 15; Notes (Box 15 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 136)
    - "My Lai and Nuremberg". Michigan Bar Association, Detroit, 1970 January 24; Notes, correspondence (Box 16 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 1)
    - "A Hippocratic Oath for the Molders of Minds". American Veterans Committee, Washington, 1970 March 21; Typescript, program, correspondence (Box 16 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 2)
    - "United States Military Intervention in Cambodia in the Light of International Law". International Conference of Lawyers, New York University, Toronto, 1970 May 22-1970 May 24; Typescripts (Box 16 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 3)